# Cian Clarke, VP Engineering

Seasoned engineering leader with 12 years of experience, focused on growing & leading technology teams.

Strong track record of hiring & scaling teams to perform at their optimum, fostering a culture of innovation & belonging. Player-coach, comfortable both deep in the code & managing those who write it.

Skills

**Soft skills:** Hiring & retention, Mentorship, Developer Empathy, Customer Empathy, Project Management, Conflict Resolution, Employee Retention

Products: Slack (inc. ChatOps), Jira, Asana, Lucidchart, Kibana, Grafana, Hubspot

AWS technologies: Lambda, Api Gateway, DynamoDB, Fargate, CloudFormation, SNS, SQS, IoT, S3, CloudFront, Cloudwatch, Codebuild, Sagemaker, Glue, Kinesis & many more AWS cloud native technologies

Programming Languages: Javascript & Python. (Previously: Swift, Objective C, Java, Go)

Frameworks: Node.js, Express (contributor), React, Redux, FastAPI

Al/ML products: ChatGPT, OpenAl, Google Dialogflow, WIT.ai, Amazon Lex, IBM Watson, RASA

**Al/ML frameworks/tools:** GPT2, GPT3, BERT, various proprietary CNN models, Juniper Notebook, Huggingface

**Certifications:** AWS Machine Learning Speciality | AWS Developer Associate

**Employment History** 

### VP Engineering at ServisBOT, Boston/Waterford

December 2019 — Present

- Architect a conversational platform that scaled to 50 enterprises & over 30 million end users
- Developed key employee initiatives leading to a near-100% employee retention rate over 6 years
- Lead the review of team structure, organising 4 teams around functional development expertise in areas such as backend engineering, frontend, data science and machine learning
- Mentor 4 engineering managers & team leads of sub-teams, aligning sprint processes and deliverables to that of the broader company
- Implement a secure Software Development Life-cycle process supporting our SOC 2 compliance & other enterprise software delivery needs of our customers
- Roll out quality management processes within the business, developing KPIs on outages, regressions & bugs reported weekly to stakeholders
- Set up communities of practice focused on R&D to encourage innovation & prevent knowledge silos across teams in areas such as AI, Serverless Architecture, and Data Science

#### Co-Founder & Engineering Manager at ServisBOT, Boston, USA

February 2017 — December 2019

Co-founded ServisBOT, a conversational Al platform.

- Deliver investor pitches of product during fundraising activity
- Deliver board presentations on engineering department progress & performance across a range of key KPIs
- Recruit engineering team from employee #1 to present strength of 13 staff, designing recruitment pipelines to suit large volumes of interview candidates within highly competitive hiring market
- Put in place agile processes for teams with differing delivery cadences & styles, responding to feedback with a focus on continually improving the process
- Develop a product suited to continuous delivery scaled from 1x large release per week to 10+ releases per day
- Architect and develop cloud-native Conversational AI platform using serverless technologies

#### Solutions Architect at Feedhenry (acq. RedHat), Boston, MA

June 2011 — January 2017

- Involved in technical due diligence for advanced partnership deals with several technology corporations eventually leading to an **\$83m acquisition** by RedHat Inc.
- Sales support in a technical capacity during customer meetings, RFP responses & delivering PoCs under stringent deadlines
- Load testing & performance tuning of mobile app backends using JMeter, Apache Bench & proprietary load testing tooling to scale applications to 10k tps
- Participate in full product development life-cycle: product requirements document, architecture & build of platform components
- Train 200 development partners across 10 worldwide sessions within EMEA, NA, and APAC.
- Deliver developer evangelism presentations to developer communities and meet-up groups, write blog posts, author video guides and give demonstrations to partner companies, provide sales support
- Participate in recruitment initiatives, including over 100 interview loops & mentoring junior developer's careers

#### Extreme Blue Intern & UI Developer at IBM, Dublin

June 2009 — September 2010

Education

Links

## BA (Mod) Computer Science, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin

September 2006 — May 2011

Personal Homepage

LinkedIn

**GitHub**